







Current Designation: SCCMAdmin Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Agnes Softech Ltd. Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead Industry: IT-Hardware & Networking

 $Key Skills: SCCM \textit{Admin}, Team \ Lead/Tech \ Lead, IT \ Infrastructure \ \textit{Management}, Windows \ \textit{Administration}, Desktop \ \textit{Management}, which is the property of the$

Support, Server Administration, End user Computing, Networking, Infrastructure Support, Technology

Solutions, Performance Tuning, IT Project Management

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Having overall 5.8 years of experience of which 4.5 years of experience as SCCMAdmin. in IT Infrastructure environment which includes Windows Administration, Desktop Support, Server Administration, End user Computing, Windows. SCCMserver maintenance and Build activities.

Good experience in software inventory, hardware inventory

Created internal and external documents.

Maintaining SCCM Patch activities.

Performing SCCM version Up-gradation.

Working towards Non-Compliance SCCMmachines.

Handling SCCM Client installations & uninstallations and troubleshooting various issues on SCCM Client.

Creating Packages, Applications and Collections.

Having knowledge on SCCMinfrastructure installation

Worked on server and windows administration of Servers 2008 R2, Server 2016, SQL server, WSUS.

Troubleshooting of primary sites and Secondary sites Issue

Troubleshooting of SMS Client Agents such as Hardware Inventory, Software Updates.

Maintaining Location Patch Compliance 95% or above.

Work Experience

Agnes Softech Ltd. as SCCM Admin

Aug 2019 to Till Date

Project & Client: Magnus Technology Solutions - Magnus Technology Solution have been serving a way array of industries over the years, by putting the latest and real time technology solutions at their fingertips.

Team Size : 6

Designation: SCCMAdmin

Responsibilities:

Managed Mcrosoft SCCMdeployments in a large-scale global environment of 5000+ users; oversaw deployments of large and complex applications targeted for mass audiences.

Plan, implement, document and maintain the system infrastructure enhancements and new technologies.

Developed software packages and provided training for other employees in deploying packages and usage of SCCM Tool.

Provided 2nd level infrastructure support, and assisted in the maintenance and troubleshooting of SCCM, and client workstations; possess a good understanding of the SCCM infrastructure including boundaries, site server roles, and parent/child relationships in order to troubleshoot SCCM related issues.

Continually look for ways to improve, optimize, and streamline software deployment process in order to ensure smooth, uninterrupted delivery to the business users.

Administered the SCCM tool set back end to keep the system running and healthy, including changes to core components and settings, software delivery, client health, reporting, boundaries, and bandwidth settings.

Generating SCCMReports on a weekly and monthly basis

Knowledge of troubleshooting of hardware and software inventory

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld Provide troubleshooting and remediation support for the entire SCCMinfrastructure.

Providing second level support for users who are experiencing problems

Full understanding of downloading and deploying MS patches using WSUS within SCCM2012 R2. Deploying updates with Systems Management Server or System Center Configuration Manager

Reporting with Systems Management Center Systems Management Server or SCCM2012

Scripting experience

Evaluate alternatives for deploying and supporting applications in a managed environment.

Experience in packaging and deploying applications and patches throughout the Enterprise. (Mcrosoft Updates and security patches)

Troubleshooting the VM machines using Virtual center and VMware Infrastructure client.

Interfaced with the various stakeholders (business sponsors, application developers, and other support personnel) to plan, deploy, troubleshoot, and support application deployments; analyzed/rectified post deployment figures to meet optimum results.

Interface directly with end users and other IT groups to ensure complete resolution of server issues reported through the Help Desk tracking system

Directed the implementation and performance tuning of Windows 2012/2016 Server environment for client's global operations.

Writing SQL scripts to actively generate reports from SCCMas requested by the management regarding machines, Licenses, Software's etc.

End user computing activities like packages, applications and patching activities for the end user machines.

Infosys Limited as SCCM Admin

Jun 2019 to Jul 2019

Project & Client: Johnson Controls - Johnson Controls is a global diversified technology and multi industrial leader serving a wide range of customers in more than 150 countries.

Team Size: 8

Designation: SCCMAdmin

Optum Global Solutions as SCCM Admin

Oct 2018 to Mar 2019

Project & Client: WellMed - WellMed is a network of doctors, specialists and professionals providing care for older

adults with over 18000 doctors' offices in Texas and Florida.

Team Size: 12

Designation: SCCM Admin

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2013

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SCCM2007, SCCM2012			
MS-SQL server			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
ENGLISH				
HINDI				
TELUGU				
PUNJABI				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.